and this is born in six minutes or less
javascript the language is actually just
a specification it's a document that
outlines the syntax and the rules of the
language to run javascript code we need
a runtime program that is going to take
our code and send those instructions to
the cpu on the web the browsers are
doing that job and outside of the
browser node.js and lino run our
javascript code until now bon is a new
all-in-one javascript runtime that the
js world is really excited about like
node.js or dino bond also runs our
javascript code but it completely
destroys node.js and dino in terms of
speed
if that wasn't enough bond is also all
in one to build a modern web application
we need node.js npm webpack bubble maybe
the typescript transpiler and even post
css bond wants to completely replace
them all
apart from being a javascript runtime
bond is also a bundler a transpiler and
a package manager a server rendering a
react application running in bonn can
handle almost 49 000 requests per second
in contrast nodejs does just a little
bit more than 16 000.
running a hundred thousand tests using
node.js and jest takes 34 seconds in
bonn with its built-in testing library
it takes only two two seconds that's
insane bonus also batteries included let
me show you what i mean by creating a
web server using bond
after installing bond with a single
command and inside of a file called
server.js
all we have to do is export an object
with the port number and the fetch
handler then we run the command bon run
server.js and if we go to our localhost
3000 we will see it work or if you want
to create a react application all you
have to do is run the command bond
create react and then bond them
done
bond also comes with a built-in sql
client and it supports a growing number
of node.js core modules like fs and path
it supports 90 of the node api and it's
compatible with the npm ecosystem so how
is bond so fast the creator of bond
spent a year building bond and
optimizing it as much as possible the
jsx and typescript transfiler the
bundler the npm client the sql client
the http client the websockets clients
they were all written from scratch using
the zig programming language
zig is a programming language with
manual memory management that in some
tests is faster than rust and it was
marketed as a better sea
bone has only one problem and that is
that it's too young so we have to wait
and see if it realizes its mission of
replacing everything based on the
reception i really think it might the js
community is exploding with bond content
tutorials and packages
let me know in the comments what is your
opinion about bond have you used it
already are you going to use it are you
excited let me know i'm going to be
reading the comments right now and don't
forget if you want to learn to code and
you want to do it for free with me then
please click the link below and i will
see you there thank you for watching as
always stay free see you on the next one
bye